<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Erik Artaz</title>
    <link>https://cv.erikartaz.work/tags/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Erik Artaz</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>it-IT</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2025 14:12:35 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://cv.erikartaz.work/tags/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why I Don’t Print My CV (And Why You Probably Shouldn’t Either)</title>
      <link>https://cv.erikartaz.work/posts/only-digital-cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2025 14:12:35 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cv.erikartaz.work/posts/only-digital-cv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a digital world that moves fast, handing out printed CVs can feel a bit&amp;hellip; dated. That’s why I’ve made a conscious decision to keep my CV only on my dedicated website.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Why?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Because a printed CV is static - it can’t reflect new projects, evolving responsibilities, or recent certifications. My online CV, on the other hand, is always current, easy to access, and better reflects my professional journey in real time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Day in the Life of an Azure FinOps Practitioner</title>
      <link>https://cv.erikartaz.work/posts/an-azure-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2025 15:55:23 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cv.erikartaz.work/posts/an-azure-journey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every day in Azure FinOps feels like navigating a massive, ever-evolving financial control tower in the cloud. My mornings usually start with dashboards—lots of dashboards. I check daily cost trends, unusual spikes, and usage anomalies across subscriptions and resource groups. It&amp;rsquo;s like being a financial detective with access to telemetry and APIs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Next comes tagging hygiene and resource governance. Are our cost allocation tags consistent? Have new untagged resources appeared overnight? If yes, it&amp;rsquo;s time to engage with resource owners or automate fixes. Clean data is the foundation of good decisions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
